# ANDREI CHOULGA

Email: nyc9293@gmail.com / LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ac317 / cell: 646-714-2422 / US Citizen for DoD

#### **EDUCATION**:

NYU Grad M.S. in Cybersecurity / GPA 3.9/4 / Started QRCP Quantum Resistant Cryptocurrency Project

**Brooklyn College:** B.S. in Computer Information Science (2006)

Certifications: Sun Microsystems (Oracle) - SCJD, SCWCD, SCDJWS, SCEA see LinkedIn for details

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

Experienced professional with 20+ years of experience in Software Development with 8+ years of experience in the Cybersecurity field, is eager to contribute to company and team success. I bring research, test-driven development, detailed planning, documentation, and dedication to my team. I thrive in both team and individual settings, and welcome challenging projects that will take my skills to the next level.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

Company: Ameritas (ameritas.com)New York, NYPosition: Cybersecurity specialist - contract10.2022-present

- Evaluated and improved security for all company services and infrastructure, worked with six different dev teams, designed/improved and deployed DMZ, Network Access Control (NAC), Software Defined Perimeter (SDP), Endpoint Detection & Response (EDR), Data Loss Prevention (DLP), configured firewall rules, automated security test scripts, troubleshooted issues by analyzing packet captures.
- Created Security Baseline Requirements based on NIST 800-53 controls, introduced threat modeling.
- Trained a security team to properly assess and triage new features for risk & work w. dev teams to remediate.
- Performed extensive **DAST** and **SAST** with API, Web and Apps, **OWASP** and **MITRE ATT&CK** based.
- via Tenable.io Interfaced with clients for whom vulnerability tests were done, explained what needed to be fixed.
- Managed public and hybrid cloud architectures in AWS, Azure
- Writing, scheduling, maintaining automated tests to check web, desktop and mobile apps (Android/iPhone) functionality in Dev, QA and Production environment.
- Performed vulnerability testing, risk analyses, security assessments on product lines for every release phase (**BurpSuite**, **Mimikatz**, **Cobalt Strike**, **PowerSploit**) Managed tests **CrowdStrike** and **Rapid7** for clients.

<u>Company: Cisco - Webex team (webex.com)</u>

Position: Cybersecurity specialist - contract

New York, NY
01.2022-08.2022

- Aligned security baseline to reflect **NIST 800-53** by breaking it down into 15 security domains for **CSDL** Cisco Secure Development Lifecycle. Consulted Engineering teams to ensure secure development is implemented in all of our products, helped select the best solution & outcomes our security posture.
- Performed DAST (Invicti, Burp, ZAP) and SAST (Veracode). Ensuring compliance w. FedRAMP, SOC 2, FISMA.
- Managed and improved Vulnerability Management lifecycle (Helped migrate from Qualys to Tenable.io)
- Worked with developers on application security relevant to: OWASP, SANS 25, Threat Modeling, API security, Validating Encryption and Key Mgmt, Validating Identity and Access Mgmt, Validating Client security, Security hygiene TPSD (Third-Party Software Digitization), Static/Dynamic analysis, X.509, OAuth.

<u>Company: NetworkShark</u>

<u>Position: Cybersecurity specialist - contract</u>

New York, NY

04.2014 - 12.2021

- Setting up **DevSecOps CICD** process automating **Qualis, Jenkins** following **NIST 800-53** controls baseline.
- Performed pen testing/DAST using Burp Suite, Acunetix, Kali Linux, Metasploit, Nessus; SAST (Checkmarx)
- Improved Docker+Kubernetes by setting up Terraform and HashiCorp Vault.

Company: SAXO Bank - Software Engineer (2009-2014) / Company: FXCM - Software Engineer (2004-2009)

### SKILLS/TOOLS:

**Languages**: C/C++, Java/J2EE, C#, Python, JavaScript (React.js/Node.JS/EmberJS/jQuery), Bash, PowerShell **Cloud**: AWS - EC2, EKS, S3, IAM, RDS, KMS, CloudFormation, CloudWatch, CloudTrail.

<u>DB</u>: Oracle, MongoDB, SQL, SQLite, MySQL, Cassandra, Redis <u>DB Tools</u>: IDERA, RazorSQL, Toad SQL **Dynamic Application Security Testing (DAST)**: Acunetix, Kali Linux, Metasploit, Nessus, Wireshark.

Static Application Security Testing (SAST): Checkmarx, GitLab, Veracode, SourceGuard, Fortify SCA, AppScan

**Network Security / Monitoring**: Splunk, Nagios, Argus, P0f. **Proxy**: Zed Attack Proxy (ZAP), Charles, Fiddler. **Web Vulnerability Scanning Tools**: Burp Suite Pro, Paros Proxy, Nmap, Nessus Professional, Arachni.

**SIEM platforms**: Splunk, Datadog, QRadar (limited: AlienVault and LogRhythm).

Build Technologies & CD/CI: Jenkins, Teamcity, Apache Ant, Apache Maven, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform.